Only one adventure gets this wild.
Jungle Cruise is a fantasy, adventure, family film
directed by Jaume Collet-Serra.
Lily Houghton enlists the aid of wisecracking skipper Frank Wolff to
take her down the Amazon in his dilapidated boat.
Together, they search for an ancient tree that holds the power to heal
– a discovery that will change the future of medicine.
Frank Wolff, played by Dwayne Johnson.
Dr. Lily Houghton, played by Emily Blunt.
Lope de Aguirre, played by Edgar Ramírez.
McGregor Houghton, played by Jack Whitehall.
Prince Joachim, played by Jesse Plemons.
Nilo, played by Paul Giamatti.
Jungle Cruise is a 2021 American fantasy adventure film
based on the Disney theme park attraction.
It stars Dwayne Johnson, Emily Blunt, Édgar Ramírez, Jack
Whitehall, Jesse Plemons, and Paul Giamatti.
Directed by Jaume Collet-Serra from a screenplay by Glenn Ficarra, John Requa, and Michael Green, it tells the alternate history of the captain of a small riverboat who
takes a scientist and her brother through a jungle in search of the Tree of life while competing against a German expedition, and cursed conquistadors.
Plans for a feature film based on the Jungle Cruise ride began in 2004.
The project lay dormant until 2011.
The original version fell through, and Johnson joined in 2015.
Blunt and the rest of the cast joined in 2018 in a revamped version, with filming
taking place in Hawaii and Georgia, from May through September that year.
The score was composed by James Newton Howard.
Following a year of post-production and a year of further delay due to the COVID-19 pandemic, Jungle Cruise premiered at Disneyland
Resort on July 24, 2021, and was released in the United States on July 30, simultaneously in theaters and digitally.
The film received mixed reviews, and was a box-office disappointment,
grossing $221 million against a budget of $200 million.
It also made $66 million over its first 30 days on Disney+ Premier Access.
The film explores themes of jungle, riverboat, 1910s,
amazon river, based on theme park ride.
The tone is lighthearted.